<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mocking Eye</title>
    <description>Description</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 22:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 22:27:40 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kaleidoscopic Haikus of the L@st Propitious Age</title>
        <description>&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
h1 { font-variant: small-caps; } 
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;epigraph&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm still working on this piece, but I think it's ready to be shared even in this draft state. Feedback is very welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;The author&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;In the 1990’s,&lt;/span&gt; my dad worked for a vector graphics startup. Sometimes he’d bring home these thick softcover books filled with glossy pages covered with nothing but pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved to get lost in page after page of idyllic azure beaches,&lt;label for=&quot;beaches&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;beaches&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; alt=&quot;Photos of beaches in a catalog.&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/beaches.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or hands being shaken, or piles of currency, or majestic vistas, or laughing multi-ethnic faces. Some of them were nothing but rows of tiny boxes barely big enough to make out. Others had bigger prints and included illustrations, or abstract patterns, or closeups of a leaf’s surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being already used to reading encyclopedias cover to cover this was just the sort of concentrated barrage of information I craved, this time in visual form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;Stock photography grew&lt;/span&gt;  in prominence throughout the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. What started as a byproduct of &lt;em&gt;assignment photography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;assignment&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;assignment&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life_(magazine)&quot;&gt;Life Magazine&lt;/a&gt; sending a photographer to take photos of something specific. &lt;/span&gt; became a major business in its own right. Stock photography served advertisers as well as both corporate and journalistic copywriters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, as the number of in-house photographers decreased, selling to stock photography companies became a viable endeavor on its own. By the late 80’s there was plenty of both supply and demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-après-moi-&quot;&gt;« Après moi… »&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;The 90’s were&lt;/span&gt; an inflection point between analog and digital and between traditional stock and &lt;em&gt;microstock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;The sort of let’s-crank-out-dozens-of-these-in-this-anonymous-studio-with-this-box-of-props stock photography you often find online these days. &lt;/span&gt;. Towards the end of the 80’s, stock photos consisted majorly of naturalistic subjects or broad conceptual ones. As more niche subjects became more common, so did more specialized—and more artistically elaborate—presentation. With &lt;em&gt;desktop publishing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desktop_publishing&quot;&gt;Desktop Publishing&lt;/a&gt; software such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adobe_PageMaker&quot;&gt;Aldus PageMaker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QuarkXPress&quot;&gt;QuarkXPress&lt;/a&gt; allowed for faster and easier layouts and typesetting. Supplanting &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phototypesetting&quot;&gt;phototypesetting&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paste_up&quot;&gt;paste up&lt;/a&gt; as the primary method of laying out graphic designed printed materials. &lt;/span&gt; becoming more common it became increasingly more affordable to produce catalogs that were coherent pieces of graphic design rather than mere indexes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/watercolor_flowers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is typified by Photonica—a Japanese stock agency founded in Tokyo in 1987 and in New York in 1990&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Photonica’s non-Japanese business was eventually &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.selling-stock.com/Article/getty-acquires-photonica-and-iconica&quot;&gt;bought by Getty in 2005&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The sophisticated colour and abstracted forms of Photonica represent a reaction against the ‘stock photo’ look; the imagery is highly specific rather than generic, and the style foregrounds the vision of individual photographers.&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#abbot94&quot;&gt;Abbot 1994&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The success of this approach led to rapid imitation such as the somewhat brazenly titled “Photo Haiku” catalog from FPG International&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;FPG International was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.selling-stock.com/Article/visual-comm-group-buys-fpg&quot;&gt;bought by Visual Communications Group (VCG) in 1997&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;. Stock photo companies themselves exemplify the common marketing paradox where they must be simultaneously both leaders and followers and so they are never shy about jumping on a trend even as they try to shape it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-à-la-recherche-&quot;&gt;« À la recherche… »&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;A couple of months&lt;/span&gt; after my son was born, I was idly thinking of things I’d like to show him some day when I thought of the stock photo catalogs of childhood for the first time in decades. And with that memory came their scent. They smelled a bit like a cross between a bookstore full of new books and a photograph freshly pulled from the paper envelope it arrived in from the photo lab &lt;label for=&quot;olds-only&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;olds-only&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;An olfactory simile with a dwindling audience. &lt;/span&gt;. I realized that after all these years, recovering that scent may be impossible but the multi-sensory aspect only bolstered my eagerness to get my hands on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;laughing-with-salads&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;laughing-with-salads&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;https://d1dlh1v05qf6d3.cloudfront.net/information/uploads/2015/11/womenlaughingatsalad.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one might imagine, searching for “stock photo catalog” isn’t very fruitful. The results are overwhelmed by the online collections offering the usual women-laughing-at-salads. Eventually, I managed to dig up some specimens on eBay and was pleasantly surprised at how cheap many were. It did make sense, since these are pretty hefty books that take up a lot of space and have no discernible target market or even ISBNs. What saved them was that while of interest mainly to professionals even when used for commerce, they are clearly not the ephemeral objects that most product catalogs are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received my first batch of eBay deliveries soon after. They came to me in San Francisco from right next door in Pacifica, though with a detour through Los Angeles due to the vagaries of intra-Pandemic USPS. The first two I leafed through were lovely and the images were even better than I remembered&lt;label for=&quot;little-boxes&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;little-boxes&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;A lot of the ones from my childhood consisted primarily of rows of tiny photo boxes, looking a little like film strip. It made for a striking effect but not much detail. &lt;/span&gt;. The third one had &lt;em&gt;the smell&lt;/em&gt; and I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;Until I began&lt;/span&gt; this search, I hadn’t really pieced together what those books in my childhood memories were, and definitely didn’t know what they were called. Heck, it was before I even learned any English. So to build my collection I had to learn who was involved in the field back then. &lt;label for=&quot;neon-tech&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;neon-tech&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; alt=&quot;90s neon tech&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/neon_tech.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The industry had been undergoing massive consolidation even in the 90’s, which means that many publishers of the catalogs no longer exist or have been absorbed by the majors. The companies that do exist no longer print paper catalogs, everything is digital. Nor do they mention the paper catalogs anywhere. Nevertheless, I was eventually able to build a by-no-means comprehensive but fairly representative &lt;a href=&quot;#the-collection&quot;&gt;collection of stock photo catalogs&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t yet discovered the specific catalogs or even the company (or companies) that printed the ones from my memories, so that quest continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been leafing through them with my son&lt;label for=&quot;age&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;age&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Who is 9 months old as I write this. &lt;/span&gt;, so they’re already accomplishing their intended purpose quite nicely. The amount, quality, and diversity of imagery rivals that of the best coffee table books and comes at a cost saving of as many as two orders of magnitude. But beyond being a cool hack, what makes these such fascinating artifacts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-ahead-look-at-the-man-behind-the-curtain&quot;&gt;Go ahead, look at the man behind the curtain!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;Before the advent&lt;/span&gt; of effortless electronic searches and infinite digital collections, stock agencies had to be able to predict what visuals would be mostly desirable. The transformation of the industry that I described above involved taking a more active role in shaping the visual language of the images, not just to respond to trends, but to predict the trends by creating them. Staying on the cusp of cool was the domain of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coolhunting&quot;&gt;coolhunters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;cf. &lt;em&gt;Pattern Recognition&lt;/em&gt; by William Gibson. &lt;/span&gt;, a pastime both popular and serious in the 90’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;smiles&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;smiles&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; alt=&quot;Smiling people&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/smiles.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
The dissonance of the positivity a user of these images would usually like to convey and the exploitation implied by the attempt makes for fascinating viewing. I can’t help but see many of the images as genuine and earnest representations despite this. A catalog with a nature theme has a chapter with images of humanity’s negative impact on the Earth, which while perfect for the downer portion of your next PowerPoint is presented wholly seriously. But beyond that sort of shallow cynicism the very attempt to dictate the visual culture indicates a sort of optimism from a time when mass-media had a semblance of direction beyond split-second reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;ptrap&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;ptrap&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; alt=&quot;P-trap Diagram&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/ptrap.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A P-trap keeps the sewer smell out.&lt;/span&gt;Although few of these catalogs represent the sort of cutting-edge material that coolhunters were tasked with digging up, they are a crystallized form of the machinery of cultural shaping, dating from the awkward teenage years of that pursuit. These days, there barely is any cool to hunt. The grizzled veterans of this field have to contend with increasingly opaque memes, eldritch TikTok trends, and Russian bots. Not an orderly Information Superhighway, but a full-duplex sewage line with no P-trap. So nowadays, stock photo websites are the interfacesto infinite archives, replacing the monkeys’ typewriters with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_single-lens_reflex_camera&quot;&gt;DSLR&lt;/a&gt;s&lt;label for=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;*&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;More and more going &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mirrorless_interchangeable-lens_camera&quot;&gt;mirrorless&lt;/a&gt;, these days. &lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;The printed catalogs&lt;/span&gt;  I’ve been collecting are a snapshot from a time when people still tried to construct a visual culture perpetual motion machine, attempting to drive the trends while being driven by them. Join me in leafing through this preserved Ouroboros of Cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kaleidoscope&quot;&gt;Kaleidoscope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Code based on: https://www.script-tutorials.com/creating-kaleidoscope-using-jquery-and-css/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title certainly hinted there may be a kaleidoscope. Picked some somewhat representative selections from my collection for this one. Please enjoy this trippy (and clearly transformative) work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your view:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:set_collection_to_pages()&quot;&gt;Look Inside&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;position: relative; top: 0.5rem&quot;&gt;☟&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;a style=&quot;margin-left: 3rem&quot; onclick=&quot;javascript:set_collection_to_covers()&quot;&gt;Judge Them By Their Covers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;position: relative; top: 0.5rem&quot;&gt;☟&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;kaleidoscope&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: right; margin-right: 1rem; font-size: 1.4rem&quot;&gt;&lt;a onclick=&quot;javascript:stop_rotation()&quot;&gt;That's enough.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#9757;&amp;#xFE0E;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;kal_main&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;kal_cont&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s1&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s2&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s3&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s4&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s7&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s8&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s9&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s10&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s11&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;ks s12&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;ksc&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr style=&quot;width: 60%; margin: 0 0 5rem 3rem;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-collection&quot;&gt;The Collection&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;the-collection&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;cover-gallery&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;cover-gallery&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; alt=&quot;Gallery of stock photo catalog covers.&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/cover_gallery.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cover Gallery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Company&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Comstock&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1994&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Encyclopedia of Stock Photography, Volume 6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Corbis&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1997&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Speaking in Visuals&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Red&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2001&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;American Mosaic 006&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;FPG International&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1993&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Photo Haiku&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Selects Volume 5: Renaissance: Exceptional Stock Photographs&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1996&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Selects Volume 3: Historical Selects: A Look at the 20th Century&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;The Stock Directory: Science + Industry&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;People: Contemporary Living&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Masterfile&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1997&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;The Green Directory 2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;The Positive Image&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Bon Voyage&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;PhotoDisc&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1996&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Resource Book 4&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Resource Book 6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Photonica&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1997&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Edition 25 “Evolution”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1999&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Edition 44&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Edition 49 “Life?”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2001&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Edition 61&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Edition 62 “Spanner”&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Sharpshooters&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1994&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Premium Stock Photography 5&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;SuperStock&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Portfolio 8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Portfolio 9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Tony Stone&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1993&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Images - Vol 5&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1994&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Images: Visions of Nature&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1995&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Images: Business and Industry&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Images - Vol 7&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Wonderfile&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;2000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;DigitalVision&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tfoot&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;†&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;Year is estimated based on when Wonderfile was spun out of Masterfile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tfoot&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
    .kaleidoscope {
        overflow: hidden;
        width: 950px;
        height: 0px;
        margin: 2rem 0;
        -webkit-transition: height 1.5s ease-in-out;
        transition: height 1.5s ease-in-out;
    }

    /* common kaleidoscope styles */

    .kal_main {
        overflow: hidden;
         -moz-border-radius: 1rem;
        -webkit-border-radius: 1rem;
        width: 950px;
        height: 950px;
        margin: auto
    }

    .kal_cont {
        width: 140%;
        height: 140%;
        left: -20%;
        top: -20%;
        position: relative;
        margin: auto
    }

    .kal_cont .ks {
        -webkit-transform-origin: right top;
        -moz-transform-origin: right top;
        -o-transform-origin: right top;
        transform-origin: right top;
        width: 50%;
        height: 50%;
        position: absolute;
        top: 50%;
        left: 0;
        z-index: 10;
        overflow: hidden;
    }

    .kal_cont .ksc {
        height: 100%;
        width: 100%;
        -webkit-transform: rotate(30deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(30deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(30deg);
        transform: rotate(30deg);
        position: relative;
        -webkit-transform-origin: left top;
        -moz-transform-origin: left top;
        -o-transform-origin: left top;
        transform-origin: left top;
        left: 100%;
        top: 0;
        background-size: cover;
        -webkit-transition: background-image 2.5s ease;
        transition: background-image 2.5s ease;
    }

    /* styles for each sector */

    .kal_cont .s1 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(-30deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(-30deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(-30deg);
        transform: rotate(-30deg);
    }

    .kal_cont .s2 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(30deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -moz-transform: rotate(30deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -o-transform: rotate(30deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        transform: rotate(30deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
    }

    .kal_cont .s3 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(30deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(30deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(30deg);
        transform: rotate(30deg);
    }

    .kal_cont .s4 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(90deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -moz-transform: rotate(90deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -o-transform: rotate(90deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        transform: rotate(90deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
    }

    .kal_cont .s5 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(90deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(90deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(90deg);
        transform: rotate(90deg);
    }

    .kal_cont .s6 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(150deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -moz-transform: rotate(150deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -o-transform: rotate(150deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        transform: rotate(150deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
    }

    .kal_cont .s7 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(150deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(150deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(150deg);
        transform: rotate(150deg);
    }

    .kal_cont .s8 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(210deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -moz-transform: rotate(210deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -o-transform: rotate(210deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        transform: rotate(210deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
    }

    .kal_cont .s9 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(210deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(210deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(210deg);
        transform: rotate(210deg);
    }

    .kal_cont .s10 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(270deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -moz-transform: rotate(270deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -o-transform: rotate(270deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        transform: rotate(270deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
    }

    .kal_cont .s11 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(270deg);
        -moz-transform: rotate(270deg);
        -o-transform: rotate(270deg);
        transform: rotate(270deg);
    }

    .kal_cont .s12 {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(330deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -moz-transform: rotate(330deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        -o-transform: rotate(330deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
        transform: rotate(330deg) matrix(-1, 0, 0, 1, 0, 0);
    }
    
    a:hover { cursor: pointer; }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
var cover_images = [
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Corbis%20American%20Mosaic%20006.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Corbis%20Red.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/FPG%20Historical%20Selects%20Vol%203.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/FPG%20People%20Contemporary%20Living.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/FPG%20Photo%20Haiku.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/FPG%20Selects%20Vol%205.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/FPG%20Stock%20Directory%20Science%20%2B%20Industry.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Masterfile%20Bon%20Voyage.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Masterfile%20The%20Green%20Directory%202.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Masterfile%20The%20Positive%20Image.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/PhotoDisc%20Resource%20Book%204.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/PhotoDisc%20Resource%20Book%20X.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Photonica%2025.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Photonica%2044.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Photonica%2049.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Photonica%2061.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Photonica%2062.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Sharpshooter%205.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/SuperStock%20Portfolio%208.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/SuperStock%20Portfolio%209.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Tony%20Stone%20Images%20Business%20and%20Industry.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Tony%20Stone%20Images%20Nature.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Tony%20Stone%20Images%20Vol%205.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Tony%20Stone%20Images%20Vol%207.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Tony%20Stone%20Signal.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Wonderfile%20DigitalVision.jpg', 
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalog_covers/Comstock%20Encyclopedia%20of%20Stock%20Photography%20Volume%206.jpg', 
];

var page_images = [
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/business.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/clouds.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/computers.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/fast_moving_business.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/fish.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/forests.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/green.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/internet_world.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/logging_industry.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/medicine.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/business_district.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/neon_tech.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/pills_etc.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/rust.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/slightly_sick.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/smiles.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/sports.jpg',
    '/assets/images/stock_photo_catalogs/watercolor_flowers.jpg',
]


var current_image = 0;
var current_collection = cover_images;

function set_collection_to_covers() {
    current_image = -1;
    current_collection = cover_images;
    document.styleSheets[2].cssRules[4].style.backgroundSize = 'cover';
    rotate_image();
}

function set_collection_to_pages() {
    current_image = -1;
    current_collection = page_images;
    document.styleSheets[2].cssRules[4].style.backgroundSize = 'contain';
    rotate_image();
}

function rotate_image() {  
    if (!rotationInterval) {
        start_rotation();
        return;
    }
    var cur_pos = $('.ks .ksc').css('background-position');
    current_image = (current_image == current_collection.length - 1) ? 0 : current_image + 1;
    document.styleSheets[2].cssRules[4].style.backgroundImage = &quot;url(&quot; + current_collection[current_image] + &quot;)&quot;;
    $('.ks .ksc').css('background-position', cur_pos);
}

function start_rotation() {
    if (stopTimeout) {
        clearTimeout(stopTimeout);
        stopTimeout = null;
        stopEverything();
    }
    $('.kaleidoscope').css('height','0px');
    $('.kaleidoscope').css('height', '980px');
    //$('.kal_main').css('height', '950px');
    rotationInterval = setInterval(rotate_image, 4000);
    $(document).on('mousemove', 'div.ks',function(e){
        e.stopPropagation();
        $('.ks .ksc').css('background-position', e.pageX+&quot;px &quot;+e.pageY+&quot;px&quot;);
    });
    rotate_image();
}

function stopEverything() {
    clearInterval(rotationInterval);
    $(document).off('mousemove', 'div.ks');
    rotationInterval = null;
    document.styleSheets[2].cssRules[4].style.backgroundImage = null;

}

function stop_rotation() {
    $('.kaleidoscope').css('height','0px');
    stopTimeout = setTimeout(stopEverything, 4000);
}

var rotationInterval, stopTimeout;
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;abbot94&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Miller, Abbot. “Pictures for Rent”. Autumn 1994. &lt;em&gt;Eye Magazine.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eyemagazine.com/feature/article/pictures-for-rent&quot;&gt;http://www.eyemagazine.com/feature/article/pictures-for-rent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200731034820/http://www.eyemagazine.com/feature/article/pictures-for-rent&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[archive]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eng, Rohn and Pickerrel, Jim. “Is the Internet for Photographers?” February 15, 1996. &lt;em&gt;Selling Stock.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.selling-stock.com/Article/internet-for-photographers&quot;&gt;https://www.selling-stock.com/Article/internet-for-photographers&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20171029143112/https://www.selling-stock.com/Article/internet-for-photographers&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[archive]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frosh, Paul. &lt;em&gt;The Image Factory: Consumer Culture, Photography and the Visual Content Industry.&lt;/em&gt; Berg, 2003.
&lt;!-- - &quot;Stock Photography.&quot; *Wikipedia.* &lt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stock_photography&gt; [&lt;sup&gt;[archive]&lt;/sup&gt;](https://web.archive.org/web/20200930070509/https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stock_photography) --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 16:56:40 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2020/11/06/kaleidoscopic-haikus-of-the-l@st-propitious-age</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2020/11/06/kaleidoscopic-haikus-of-the-l@st-propitious-age</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alternative Libraries of San Francisco</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This Valentine’s day we made it a Library Lovers’ Day and visited two of my favorite libraries in SF:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-1-the-prelinger-library&quot;&gt;Stop 1: The Prelinger Library&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ww1.hdnux.com/photos/40/31/02/8491192/3/920x1240.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikiwand.com/en/Prelinger_Library&quot;&gt;Prelinger library&lt;/a&gt; is basically the personal research library of archivist power-couple &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Megan_Prelinger&quot;&gt;Megan Prelinger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Rick_Prelinger&quot;&gt;Rick Prelinger&lt;/a&gt;. It’s open one day every week, and two weekends a month. It uses its own unique classification scheme and hosts both digital and non-digital books as well as pretty large collection of ephemera. The classification scheme encourages browsing and discovery. I always discover a new treasure whenever I’m here. Tonight it was the &lt;em&gt;Manual of the Corporation of the City of New York (1860)&lt;/em&gt; which in addition to seating maps of 19th century politicians and minutes of meetings has amazing foldout engravings of daily life in New York City in the early to mid 1800s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prelingerlibrary.org/home/&quot;&gt;Prelinger Library – Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-2-the-mechanics-institute-library&quot;&gt;Stop 2: The Mechanics’ Institute Library&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.sfgate.com/blogs/images/sfgate/dinkelspiel/2009/03/25/mechanics_institute.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started as the Gold Rush was dying out with a vocational and technical focus, The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/San_Francisco_Mechanics%27_Institute&quot;&gt;Mechanics’ Institute Library&lt;/a&gt; is the oldest library on the West Coast, and it contains the oldest chess club in the United States. This library is open to the public, but membership requires a fee. 1854 isn’t that old even by East Coast standards, but this place has about as much gravitas as this part of the country can muster. I especially like their large-format book collection, which is pleasure to leaf through on the nice leather couches. Flipped through books on Roman armor, birds of prey, Tarot, and menswear (which has an introduction by Terrence Stamp).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.milibrary.org/&quot;&gt;Mecahnics’ Institute Library &amp;amp; Chess Room – Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 18:22:36 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2016/02/14/alternative-libraries-of-san-francisco</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2016/02/14/alternative-libraries-of-san-francisco</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Living Room</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last month I had the pleasure of joining fellow artists, designers and builders in a project that debuted at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ourcity.is/oakland/&quot;&gt;Our City: Oakland&lt;/a&gt; public design fair. It stood welcoming all for 3 days, Feb 4 – Feb 6, 2016.
This was our artist statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Living Room sprouts from the ground in the middle of Frank Ogawa Plaza. An open countertop wraps around the wall, directing pedestrians in and out of the interior, where they can share their photo or enjoy the shifting display while playing House. The walls open like two arms into the city, suggesting that all public space can be sites for gathering and play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Living Room creates a space where people of Oakland come together to play and exist together as one community, one family. Portraits of passersby magically appear, arranged as family photos, in a warm playful set that transforms the city’s exterior into a shared space we all call home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me it was a very fulfilling experience that I hope to repeat in a few different ways over the coming months. Visitors seemed to enjoy it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to thank my collaborators: Albert Kong, Alex Kryzanowski, Min J Yoon, Kat Meler, Jessica Lachenal, Justin Tang, and Aaron Wynn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-was-not-just-a-dream&quot;&gt;It was not just a dream:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after it was first built:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/livingroom-after-build.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evening on the first night:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/livingroom-evening.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Night Room:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/livingroom-night.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 14:34:25 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2016/02/07/a-living-room</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2016/02/07/a-living-room</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Revelations and Miscellania</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Switching all the world’s cars to driverless at once would save more lives this year than immediate world peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sports-corner&quot;&gt;Sports Corner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Kabaddi&quot;&gt;Kabbadi&lt;/a&gt; is an Indian full-contact team sport where you have to take a breath, then chant “kabbadikabbadikabbadi…” as you run into the other team’s territory and try to tag them. The chanting is to prove you’re still on your first breath. Once you tag a member of the other team, they try and prevent you from exiting their territory. India vs. Pakistan in the 2014 World Cup:
adfsd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/RSnP9z99I9M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-musical-interlude&quot;&gt;A Musical Interlude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the band Too Many Zooz (you’ve probably seen videos of them preforming in NYC’s Union Square subway station) doing their Brasshouse thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/2saIopqJCKQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ur-kel-masters&quot;&gt;The Ur-kel Masters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Videogame mashup of Family Matters and Star Control II.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 10:59:14 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2016/01/25/revelations-and-miscellania</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2016/01/25/revelations-and-miscellania</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Posts will continue until morale improves. -mgmt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Going to resume posting, collating smaller thoughts I’ve had and sometimes posted on other media. Perhaps it’ll encourage me to expand on some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cult becomes a religion when you can be one just on holidays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being kind is better than being nice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’ve known me for any length of time you’ve probably heard me crack my knuckles.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Here’s what actually happens: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0119470&quot;&gt;Real-Time Visualization of Joint Cavitation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;But don’t worry, it’s safe: &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.mit.edu/V129/N41/ignobels.html&quot;&gt;Ig Nobel Winner Shows Knuckle Cracking Won’t Cause Arthritis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikiwand.com/en/ASCII_art&quot;&gt;ASCII&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikiwand.com/en/ANSI_art&quot;&gt;ANSI art&lt;/a&gt; is old hat. New hotness? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/PETSCII&quot;&gt;PETSCII&lt;/a&gt; art. The thing that really does it for me is it contains triangles.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://csdb.dk/event/?id=2139&amp;amp;sort=rating&quot;&gt;gallery/competition of PETSCII art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikiwand.com/en/Ingressive_sound&quot;&gt;Pulmonic ingressives&lt;/a&gt; in the wild: &amp;lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/URgdIAz4QNg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 14:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2015/05/13/posts-will-continue-until-morale-improves-mgmt</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2015/05/13/posts-will-continue-until-morale-improves-mgmt</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User Interfaces</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;User interfaces matter. I was watching a recent episode of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Taste&quot;&gt;The Taste&lt;/a&gt;, and one of the contestants’ meatloaf just wasn’t cooking. Every time she went back to her oven she’d see the touch screen display 350F. She would slide the touch-based temperature slider to 550F and walk away. But when she’d return, the temperature was back to 350F.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time she did this I had a suspicion. The second time she went to back to the screen, I was able to confirm it. The temperature selection screen had an OK button on the bottom right. Just like it’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modal_dialog&quot;&gt;modal dialog&lt;/a&gt;. She would set the temperature, but walk away without tapping that all-important OK button so the temperature wasn’t actually being adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User interfaces use metaphors in order to access shortcuts you already have in your brain. This is why &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skeumorphism#Digital_skeuomorphs&quot;&gt;skeumorphism&lt;/a&gt; is used in the design of digital interfaces, so you don’t have to learn a completely new way to perform a task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most simple interfaces is a lever. It &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affordance&quot;&gt;affords&lt;/a&gt; manipulation and it augments human capability: you can exert greater force. But it’s also a metaphor for what a user interface is. If an interfaces does not enable enhancement of capacity, it is actively a hinderance. To avoid &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cargo_cult#Metaphorical_uses_of_the_term&quot;&gt;cargo cult design&lt;/a&gt; always consider what you attempting to enable and how much leverage you are contributing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 23:04:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2014/01/12/user-interfaces</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2014/01/12/user-interfaces</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mirrorshades</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally reading Bruce Sterling’s cyberpunk short story collection &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0441533825/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0441533825&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=themoceye-20&quot;&gt;Mirrorshades&lt;/a&gt;. It’s commonly referred to as the definitive collection of what was then a movement and is now more of a distinct sub-genre. I was expecting to read a collection of hyper stylized and at times outdated stories, akin to how much of William Gibson’s Sprawl trilogy reads now (they’re still awesome, but are clearly an artifact of their times, while a lot of good SF from the same era manages to escape that fate). To my delight I got something much fresher. Covering a nice swathe of the movement, it gives a pretty comprehensive and non-stereotypical example of the style and the themes of cyberpunk. There’s still a lot of arguing about whether everything in it is cyberpunk (for example Gibson’s Gernsback Continuum, which still reads fresh) but I think it manages to capture the feelings of cyberpunk with a nuance and scope I wasn’t really expecting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 17:21:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2013/03/03/mirrorshades</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2013/03/03/mirrorshades</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Solving a Major Problem -- Bras</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like learning about other people’s problems. I particular like learning about problems from people who have different problems than mine and one of the most common and persistent of those is the issue of bras. Many women told me about it and complaints were near universal and came from all quarters. I’ve specifically asked a lot of women about their experiences with bras to better understand and also did research on the state of the art of design, engineering and manufacturing of bras. This is something that affects women with breasts of all sizes–it isn’t restricted to women with big breasts. I realized recently that although I’d love to work on this problem, without some help I can’t do it. I’m not a domain expert in several of the fields required, though I’ve gone into some depth on the subject, so writing about it would perhaps inspire someone to either join me or take it up on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An important note:&lt;/em&gt; It is common amongst engineers and programmers to wade into a new domain with a savior complex, “we’ll fix this for you with our fresh perspective!”. On a slightly different slant, a lot of women have experience &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Mansplain&quot;&gt;mansplaining&lt;/a&gt;. I’m trying very explicitly to not be doing either of these. I’d like this to be an overview of what I’ve discovered and what I think is a good solution. I’m not swooping from above magically delivering bra salvation to the helpless female masses. I just haven’t seen these ideas put together before and thought folks might be interested. Just wanted this to be clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bras are required to perform these core functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mold the breasts into the a shape desired by the wearer (usually dictated by changing fashions, but on occasion alternative ones are desired)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reflect the look desired by the wearer when viewed without clothing (this would sometimes be “more attractive” and others, such as with sport bras, less so).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide support and comfort allow for a wider range of vigorous activities than some women can easily accomplish without. This includes eliminating chafing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to perform #1 and #2 bras are form-fitting so as to not be prominent under clothing. Form-fitting is best achieved with stretchy fabrics, which would make either #3 or #2 hard (sports bras for example sacrifice #2). Underwires were introduced to be able to transfer most of the difficult task of providing support to rigid elements made of plastic or metal. If a form-fitting item is not stretchy it will always be uncomfortable if it is not custom made. This is the core reason bras are so uncomfortable. It’s the only clothing item of this sort I can think of that is commonly worn. Imagine briefs made from dress shirt fabric. That is not a pleasant thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bra sizing is terrible. The cup size of a 32C and a 34C is of a different size even though it’s designated as C. The way most companies design bras these days is that they a group of women that they used to measure and now usually perform 3D laser scans on called the &lt;em&gt;model pool&lt;/em&gt;. Using the model pool they derive their band size to cup size function. This means that the particular function varies from manufacturer to manufacturer. So not only are the sizes themselves inconsistent between manufacturers the &lt;em&gt;steps&lt;/em&gt; are also different since the sizing function would vary by their particular pool and how they segmented it. On top of this there are the core issues of breast asymmetry and placement: The vast majority of women’s breasts are asymmetrical and the distance between the breasts varies a lot. These are not taken into account in the sizing and adjustment for them is minimal if available at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, bras are uncomfortable and under the current model can’t possibly be made comfortable. A less egregious but annoying aspect of the bra industry is that they subtly imply but never state that the bras might affect breast sagging (the technical term for which is &lt;em&gt;ptosis&lt;/em&gt;). Repeated studies by the industry have shown this to not be the case (breasts will sag with age regardless of bra wear), so they never claim it outright but merely hint. Additionally, there are medical effects such as back pain and problems with the lymph nodes that result from imperfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a problem that ranks highly on both the scales of &lt;em&gt;pain&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;persistence&lt;/em&gt;. This is a daily issue that causes many women a lot of suffering. It’s a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must be able to create a custom bra for each woman. My proposed method involves performing a 3D scan of the breasts from which a custom pattern is derived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state of 3D scanning as evidenced by products such as the Kinect or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://leapmotion.com/&quot;&gt;Leap&lt;/a&gt; is such that large and slow laser scanning equipment is no longer necessary. Small units can be built and placed inside changing rooms in existing stores or perhaps in some sort of booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, a bra is an item that applies certain force vectors to from a source shape to a target shape. Current design techniques in the industry treat the breasts as liquids filling a form. The form is anchored to a body and they perform simulations not very different from those involved in other structures such as bridges to ensure forces dissipate in optimal ways throughout the bra and through the body. This sort of analysis would still be necessary, but with a 3D scan of the breasts we can create an accurate model of the breasts. So one woman might need additional support in a particular angle while another who may share her exact band and cup size would not, merely due to the differences in shape and volume which are now available!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advances in textile manufacturing also provide potentially interesting elements. Better weaving machines are able to construct fabrics with custom 3D structures so that things like the fabric’s elasticity can vary throughout without varying the amounts of a different material. Manufacturing supply chains, and custom orders are increasingly more common, easy and cheap. We get the additional advantage of being able to respond to changing fashions in both the desired target shape and appearance more easily than traditional approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to get something like this done, one would need to be good at 3D scanning, the math required to do the tensor math for the breast shaping, the math for turning those force vectors into a pattern, the math and engineering required to optimize the patterns and the necessary textile manufacturing instructions, and the business connections to get the manufacturing done well and cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A custom bra is necessary. There’s just no other way to fulfill all 3 core tasks. I’d love for someone to tackle this. Please do contact me with any thoughts you might have on this, it’s more important than it might seem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit:&lt;/em&gt; I really have been researching this fairly deeply for over a year, this is just meant to be a an introduction, so pardon the lack of nuance and depth. Happy to discuss any specific aspects further if anyone’s interested!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 21:59:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2013/02/24/solving-a-major-problem-bras</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2013/02/24/solving-a-major-problem-bras</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Job!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just thought I might make it a point to mention I recently joined the engineering team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.comprehend.com/&quot;&gt;Comprehend&lt;/a&gt;, a fellow Y Combinator company. We make analytics software targeting pharmaceutical companies in an industry that’s filled with balkanized solutions. Helping tackle the byzantine challenges involved in clinical trials should be interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, I must add that my opinions and comments and do not represent my employer in any way shape or form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 20:22:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2013/02/03/new-job</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2013/02/03/new-job</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reading everything stdin in a bash script</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In trying to get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://collectd.org/&quot;&gt;collectd&lt;/a&gt; instance to send me alerts, I found out that I didn’t know how to just read everything that might be piped into a bash script via standard input. You can read line by line easily using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; command. Just looping over it seemed pretty horrendous to me until I discovered an elegant way to do it that’s perhaps canonical, but doesn’t seem to pop up via quick googling:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;VALUE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$VALUE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$(cat)&lt;/code&gt; is a shorthand for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$(cat /dev/stdin)&lt;/code&gt;, so presumably you can use this to read from stderr by pointing it at &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/dev/stderr&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy piping!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 14:27:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>/posts/2013/01/22/reading-everything-stdin-in-a-bash-script</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/posts/2013/01/22/reading-everything-stdin-in-a-bash-script</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
